I believe HDMX is based on like an older
framework which has like it's at least
10 years old or something really I
didn't look into it that much but yeah I
thought it was new too but I guess it's
just popular now it's getting popularity
because somebody is popping off on
Twitter with the HDMX account like
they're always roasting people or like
getting some sort of viral meme which is
super hilarious I think
[Music]
[Applause]
hey guys real quick if you are listening
to this episode on April 25th 2024 you
are not too late to get on the hardly
strictly security Conference held by
project Discovery it is also happening
today from 11:00 a.m. eastern or GMT
minus 4
uh so get in on that goodness there's
going to be lots of awesome speakers
talking about open source security and
very relevant topics for uh bug bounty
hunters so if you're interested in that
head over to nu. that's
nx.
hs24 it's a little bit of a tongue
twister hss2 24
nu. hs24 to get on on that conference
and I believe they're going to be
releasing the content afterwards for
review um so even if you didn't get to
see it today or if you're listening to
this episode later you should be able to
see the content from the uh conference
uh on their website so if you're
interested in that check it out and
we'll get back over to the Pod all right
so so let me preface this one with um I
get a DM in my inbox a couple weeks ago
Matias says Justin I've got something
fresh for you man I've got something
good to bring on the Pod so that's why
we're here today um Matias is going to
come and drop some I don't know so
you've been doing some research into HTM
X recently right and there's like four
or five oh no it starts with zero here
so there's five five uh individual
things you've got here that that came
out of that research so um well first I
guess let me let me ask this man what
made you look into HTM X in the first
place uh to sort of spur This
research
well
I don't remember exactly how I stumbled
upon it but I I didn't uh start by
wanting to look for bugs or like
security issues when with using hmx I'm
actually part of a couple of ctfs that
that are run each year and I wanted a
better or maybe not better but easier
for me to use uh frontend framework uh
to quickly build uh small applications I
guess and I felt the this kind of
changing approach that is HDMX was nice
so I started building with it and then
uh C curiosity got the best of me I
guess okay so cuz we we we kind of
dissed on it on the Pod a couple weeks
ago you know or maybe it was a couple
months ago at this point we were like
okay like let's just make JavaScript you
know HTML here like like how could this
go wrong um but I mean so you like it
from an architecture perspective is it
easy to write is it is it a good
framework yeah I think so it's it's very
easy I I
wrote like of all the only three I guess
but still three functional web
applications small that I wrote I wrote
the zero lines of JavaScript and that
was lovely wow that's and that's coming
from a guy who's like I like ypt yeah
that's but it's just actually
programming in it yeah and it's just um
I don't know it feels
more more lightweight less um layers of
abstractions and that's that means
generally that it's easier to understand
and then that I like so cool man very
cool yeah no I mean I you originally the
idea looked a little bit sketchy to me
um but I could definitely see how trying
to eliminate all these like okay now we
got to deal with props and we got to
deal with all these little like you know
little layers of extraction that come
with all of these um JavaScript
Frameworks could be attractive and
there's actually been a a movement that
I've kind of seen in the developer
Community um of just moving back to like
just straight vanilla JavaScript and
jQuery you know at this point I've seen
it um on Twitter a decent bit so I don't
know that that we need to go all that
that far in the other direction but
seeing something that's a little bit
more lightweight is uh is definitely
pretty cool so very nice yeah I I I
agree and I think that it might not be a
bad idea to use more of the buil-in
features of the browser not only
everything has to go through through Aja
and then be rendered on the client side
I I guess that's the biggest the
difference between traditional single
page application Frameworks and
something like the HDMX is that like the
mix of the data and the markup is
expected to be made on the server
instead of the client just like the good
old days or bad old days yeah however
you however you remember
them that's good all right man so let's
walk through some of these some of these
things you found okay so zero was I like
how he's got the list here he's got uh
you know zero dot in the doc zero dot
you know one dot two dot three dot four
dot I will say the the zero dot is the
uh is the title so we've got four
individual um things that we were going
to walk through here one of them is a uh
is a CSP byass using uh HDMX so kind of
walk me through that if you
would yeah so I should have pressed my
notes better because but we'll just take
it as we go so the thing is when using
HDMX and specifically if you want to use
uh its triggers um like a custom HX
Trigger or like HX on um that would be
equivalent to like an own load or
something okay uh you kind of have
to or like it's using evil um internally
so if you want to use HDMX in that kind
of way uh at the same time as you're
using CSP you kind of you kind of forced
to have unsafe Evol enabled in your um
directives and because of
that it's becomes like a kind of a
Global CSP bypass uh because even though
CSP protects you again against unsafe in
line like an actual on error you can
just replace that with like the HDMX
equivalent and there you go okay so
that's like one thing to note and like
all of these things are like I I wanted
to figure
out what type of issues could arise um
only by using HDMX so like if some other
framework was used or if there was well
in the JS the bug or problem U didn't
exist but it exists only because we're
now in this uh World hmx solid that that
makes sense and actually taking a step
step back from that before we double
click into that one um you you did you
run all of these problems that are in
the dock right here in the CTF that you
recently
did um not all of them but I I there was
like three of them combined CU that's i
b as much as my head could wrap around
into an exra challenge without like
screwing it up the way somewhere nice
yeah yeah it was good it was there was a
bunch of solers too and new people seem
to like it so very good yeah client side
ctfs are are interesting because I I
love a lot of clientside bugs and I've
kind of been talking with some people
doing some cfish stuff and it's like
okay well how do we how do we get a flag
I guess they have to like submit it into
a head you know headless Chrome and have
them actually you know call some
function or something to get the flag
return it back um but it is cool to see
client side client side um stuff popping
out in the CTF World um okay so this one
this sort of gives me vi The Vibes of
that um angular CSP bypass where it's
like you can if you have like a
whitelisted host you can import angular
from that host and then you can run some
ng- knit or something like that and it
will run JS code under the the pretext
of that angular is this kind of like the
the HTM X equivalent of
that yes yes I would say and and I think
that if if you would ask the authors of
the framework it's like expected but
still it's from it makes a security
feature that is built into the browser
slightly less effective you could say
and and also I want to preface like most
of these if not all of these are based
on the fact that you can get HDMX on
some page uh to fetch your page via an
direct or just straight up fetching your
page and that's kind of dis encouraged
in the documentation so it's kind the
argument from the HDMX side is kind of
like well you should never fetch cross
origin data with this framework what
what do you mean see like yeah like are
doing request or are you saying
like they are doing a request internally
but since this is since HDMX is BAS the
the data transfer of HDMX is just like
HTML get the HTM raw HTML from the
server and then put it on the page ah so
inherently that would be like an xss if
you just fetch something off off the off
domain ah sure okay so you need some
sort of like client side path traversal
or something like that that's returning
that's allowing you to return data but I
mean couldn't you also just have a
traditional Dom xss sync of sorts in
this environment or is that yeah and and
then then also or like often see with
the angular situation you've got an HTML
injection uh or something that that has
a and you need to bypass a CSP and they
actually explicitly import uh angular
for the purpose of doing the CSP bypass
is that also something that's popular or
or possible here yes yes exactly so it's
like if you if you follow the
documentation to a T and build your
application as a pure single page
application like like whichever route
you request on the page you will get the
exact same HTML back let's say then
you're kind of okay but that's very
difficult to do if you want to build
something that's bigger than like hello
world yeah so okay and so you know
somehow we achieve HTML injection or
some sort of uh you know client side
PSAL based sync of sorts and then we um
you know we're running into something
where unsafe inline isn't in place but
unsafe inval is and we're able to use
this gadget um using uh HT htx on htx
load the the onload equivalent Handler
um to actually pop some some uh some
code is that accurate that's right okay
that's exactly right solid and and so
then for for developers using HDMX or or
for hackers looking to exploit HDMX
based Pages what kind of
CSP because they have to do unsafe inal
essentially if they're using any of
these on onload handlers right
CSP want to see if if they want to use
these uh triggers and stuff uh they have
to but otherwise and and you don't have
to build it like that uh otherwise there
is a a uh HDMX configuration flag to
turn this eval stuff oh really oh
interesting yeah unfortunately that's
not enabled by default and we'll we'll
come to another in my perspective
insecure defaults later
also so if there's something I would
suggest that the um HDMX developers
would change but this specific it would
be to have this eval I I forget exactly
what it's called but it's called like
use eval or not let's it I love that
setting use eval or not yeah well
it's that's great that that's hilarious
um and and and so does this have to be
the the other question that pops into my
head about this specific first instance
and by the way for those of you
listening you know we're not going to
really I kind of read out the code on
that last one but like we're not going
to continue to read out the code for
what this looks like so we're going to
talk about it at a conceptual level and
then we will have these um written in
text in the hacker notes um on the ctbb
doow blog um so head over there for the
actual text version of all of these
where you can see this uh this these
partial solutions to the CTF that Matias
is dropping and also um this cool
research done on
HDMX um okay solid so that makes sense
and the only other question that that
comes into my head on on this one is
like there doesn't have to be any like
parent tags defining that this is like a
um because I know like in some
environments there's like an NG app or
something in angular that you have to
have defined but if I do like a like a
script source to include uh uh HTM X and
then I just do this image tag with this
HX on hand
here that will pop in in this
environment yeah in this uh framework
it's like a there's an upt out instead
of an optin and we'll get to why the opt
out this doesn't work but all right cool
and also just noting the configuration
flag was called allow evil allow almost
right yeah oh no that is not what we
that is not what you want to see from a
security perspective um very interesting
uh okay so next one up on the list um
dude this one's pretty interesting so
you've got a way to convert client side
response header injection to xss using
this
framework that's right and and we
realized actually during the CDF that
I'm not the first one to talk about this
and let's just press first this I I
might not be the first to know about any
of this but in any case uh yeah so one
thing that we can't do in a regular xss
world is that if we can control
the page that is fetched even and only
control the response headers and not the
response body that cannot lead at least
from what I know in modern browsers to
xss straight
up I'm making a face I I want to say
there is one way with like a link header
I want to say did does that sound
familiar to you at
all no okay all right but but I'm not s
of through there might be but not that
go go do your talk about this one real
quick I'm going to just look at my other
Tab and see if I can find because I I
want to say I tweeted about something a
while back and someone was like yeah you
can use this link header and like SVG
some anyway go ahead so this essentially
client side um header injection this one
can actually bring you to to xss using
IF HDMX is on the
page yeah exactly so if you can make
HDMX fetch um something cross the region
from from your side it's kind of like
xss by default um but sometimes you can
control uh not the origin that it will
fetch but you can control the path um
because it's do taking it from location
path name or something and if there's
some path where you can inject the
response header
um then you can make exercise with that
because there are special response
headers in HDMX to control the framework
and like tell it to do a history push
date for example or really in this
specific yeah in this specific case it's
called HX
redirect which is used to tell it to
make a make a hard redirect let's say
like a browse browser in N the redirect
and that one doesn't check if it's like
a HTTP or H just do like HX redirect
JavaScript
hello wow okay so you can I mean it just
pretty much does a window location at H
with that whatever is in the cont that
header that's right that's right wow and
so kind of specific but if it's HDMX and
you can make it you can control the path
that it um fetches but you cannot
control the origin where it will fetch
it and that one in some path has a
response to injection then you have a ex
okay so this can't happen then at the
sort of top level page so I'm I'm
thinking like say for example we have um
um you know sort of like that fresque
research where it's like you you've got
some sort of faulty reverse proxy or
something like that and you're able to
do a new line you know do a space uh in
the URL you know you do percent 20 htttp
you know 1.1 or sl11 new line you do
something right but you can't for some
reason get down to the body if that body
contains HX redirect or if that header
contains HX redirect and then that body
includes the the script that's not going
to happen this is only in the scenarios
where um HTM X is doing that thing where
it like reaches out to the server and
downloads some HTML and then processes
it afterwards is that accurate yes yes
that's accurate gotcha um but also um it
it could work
in in if if there's like an OP
redirect ah which is kind of good good
to know too cuz cuz like you you can xss
via HDMX by using redirect because it
will follow it that that's that is
interesting so so I guess that also
leads me to a thought I don't know how
much I forget if we discussed client
side path traversal or how familiar you
are with client side path traversal um
because since it's sort of a new is
vulnerability type but in your in your
experience working with HTM X did you
see any propensity for client side path
traversal um you know where is is there
any sort of system where um it's by
default encoding slashes and backs
slashes and stuff like that when being
put in the path or when a path is being
dynamically generated with user
input not that I can think of I didn't
really look at it too but also a lot of
the paths that will be used they are
actually um put together let's say on
the on the server side oh really but
yeah since it's it's putting together
the
user data or or data from the database
or whatever and the HTML over there
instead of in the client so there's no
loading like uh parsing the location
search and doing stuff interesting but
but there might be there might be I I
just don't know and and and so those
paths okay so this is actually really
starting to feel more traditional and
this is this is I'm starting to actually
see the picture of it now I wasn't as
familiar with the HDMX um architecture
but essentially this is this is sort of
like a hybrid between traditional
structure where you're just dumping back
a bunch of HTML and you're refreshing on
every single page and the modern day
sort of Ajax based fetch based structure
but but it it's actually you're passing
in some some parameters to it it's
actually doing the full HTML generation
on the server side and then dumping that
back from an A from an Ajax request from
the client side and then that's
populating the the body of the
Dom it doesn't need to be the body it
can be an element and that's of the
thing CU you can think of like a a a
hyperlink like an AAG like what does it
do okay it sends a request to the server
and it takes that and it replaces the
whole page with HTML yeah and HDMX
allows you to do that but only for
certain parts of the page
interesting that's kind of how I think
about it it's this is this is odd this
is an odd odd little little framework
here I wonder if this is uh I wonder if
is there like a billion requests that
get generated with this cuz every single
component needs to be like a server side
request to get like the piece that fills
in that piece and that piece and that
piece
or um I wouldn't say I'm very good at
building it's yet so maybe I shouldn't
answer that but for me it went pretty
well like I tried to build the what is
that called like an infinite scroll and
that kind of messed my head
up I'm sure it's possible if you're a
better programmer than me yeah Ma is
like yeah you know it's about 600 600
requests to pay it's like I'm not great
at it but I feel like
yeah well in terms of performance of
course you it's inevitable that you lose
out because all of the computation that
goes into mixing and matching all of
this HTML stuff now has to happen on the
server just like it used to be yeah that
I guess that's I guess that's more of
the point of these sort of layers of
extraction that we did in the first
place why we moved away from that
traditional structure is like we want
more performant code for these you know
applications that were scaling in the
you know 2010s area right uh and before
and uh and we needed to have have them
consume less bandwidth so we try to you
know create a structure that isn't as
verbose as HTML and Trust JavaScript on
the client side which is loaded once to
deal with all the formatting and stuff
and now with this we're kind of going
back in and redoing and doing more of a
you know server side generated thing I I
wonder why they made that design
decision and
and uh you know if they're expecting
this to be used in high performance
applications or
not um well first of all I don't think
the bandwidth is as big big as a problem
as it was before and second of all I
don't think we managed to Sol solve that
problem very well if you look at the
like uh the web packed monsters meab so
yeah but in any case also I think um I I
believe HDMX is based on like an older
framework which has like it's at least
10 years old or something I didn't look
into it that much but yeah I thought it
was new too but I guess it's just
popular now it's getting popularity
because somebody is popping off on
Twitter with the HDMX account like
they're always roasting people or like
getting some sort of viral meme which is
super hilarious I think to see a uh you
know a front-end framework um really
just kind of popping off in that
perspective is really
odd yeah that's it's fun account for
sure yeah um Okay cool so we've got the
that HX redirect that can be helpful in
some that can be a quick win in some
client side Pat troversial is
environments um and then what else is on
the ne next is on the list here oh
bypassing HX disable Okay so tell me a
bit about
this um I don't know if you have the
dock up or not
but I had my notes so but I guess I
switched around the okay so HX disable
is kind of like remember how we talked
about angular and and NG app yeah yeah
and and I said that oh actually this is
like more of an opt out instead of an
opin and so HX disable is supposed
to well disable any HDMX
functionality uh within Children's of
that
tag um and it's even recommended on
their security page let me try and find
it HDMX yeah but it says like hey you
shouldn't let users create arbitrary
HTML uh but like this is what you can do
at least to turn off the HDMX stuff and
then you have to worry about the other
stuff on the server side
um which I agree with
but in terms of effectiveness of this HX
disable is just not implemented very
holistically so what happened was that
they changed how they did um
what what is that called
um the syntax I guess of triggers so it
used to be like HX on and then you
specify it in there like HX on error
colon alert one for like on error alert
one but now there's like a new way and
I'm not sure how old it is but that's
what the code told me so you can instead
do HX Das on column error so that's like
the whole attribute name equals alert
for ah or a large one okay and this new
new type of uh way of specifying these
uh uh these triggers is just the
disabled code just doesn't look for
those it it just doesn't work no no
just yeah yeah that's so oh no are they
are they are they literally just doing
like string checks here like like find
no no no but they are just like it's
like one part of the code is doing all
of the
regular old let's say handlers and then
instead of implementing the new handlers
inside of that they implemented it like
the line under in the code but in there
there's no this HX disable stuff so it's
kind of messy o okay and so yeah I think
I think their heart was at the right
place when they started this feature but
it needs to be reworked and it still
doesn't I mean this just deals with HX
related or HDMX related functionality it
doesn't necessarily relate to um other
other things like just normal
traditional crossy scripting and stuff
like that no it's like a if you really
want to do that you should fix it with
some framework uh but to
avoid
okay I like that you said that uh oh uh
oh uh oh why do you like that I said
that because that's exactly what I
thought too okay so if you really can't
avoid use regenerated HTML okay maybe
you for whatever reason but you can
maybe use like something that is
state-ofthe-art like don't purify to to
try and fix it but there's a really
unfortunate thing here in terms of using
dump purify for HDMX and I had this in
the challenge too and it's
that optionally you can prefix all of
the uh HDMX attributes with data Dash so
they that they look like data attributes
and it just happens so to be that
everything starting with data Dash is
allowed by default in D
purify so D purify don't work out of the
books on anything HDMX wow okay so if
you can man there's some possibilities
here then because I recently ran into a
case where it's like um pretty strict
CSP uh and actually our injection was
happening at in in the script Source uh
in the source attribute of a script tag
and so we could import various stuff and
we could even break out of the script
tag and stuff like that but um the way
that the CSP was was implemented it's
like okay we can only import from the
specific host and uh you know we can't
do unsafe in line or whatever so in this
sort of situation that would that would
work out that would work out really well
interesting okay and and and even if if
there was D purify in the specific
scenario because you could just D purify
isn't going to prevent you from
continuing that Source tag that you had
and then you could uh add this specific
um down purify proof uh tag that you've
got here essentially it's just the data
Dash and then the normal HX on right
version of this that's right and before
I forget shout out to rioot tuck who was
the first I think
to this discover that scenario with d
purify versus are you kidding me wow
that's crazy that is uh wait in specific
in the HDMX
thing yeah oh wow very cool D he's
everywhere man I don't understand how
this guy does he was just like crushing
it in the live hacking event too I was
like neck and- neck with him in this
past live hacking event and he's like
also just doing freaking HDMX research
on the side like geez come on man yeah
know for sure dude's D's got a brain
yeah really really does yeah but this
does make me also think of another um
piece of research that we talked about
on the potta while back which was that
that whole uh masat kinugawa research on
um how he did the teams um let me see if
I can pull it up because he also had
something similar to this there where he
was able to use a data attribute in
angular to pop the xss did you see that
nice no no I let me pull this up for you
really quick and I also did find the
other thing that I was looking for as
well um that allow that uh this is just
so ridiculous it's slide 30 in this uh
this thing I'm sending you right here
um yeah there you go check check that
out check out slide 30 how he ends up
popping it uh here is oh it's not 30
actually is it
31 uh no it's it's 33 slide 33 he he has
essentially in in angular you can put
the NG andit inside of the
class inside of the class tag right so
you've got and the the payload he uses
here is strong class equals ng- knit
colon xss payload here and and he goes
from class attribute injection to xss on
angular which is just absolutely
mindboggling um it just makes me think
of this because it's not similar uh
exactly because data attributes are very
dissimilar to the class attribute but um
that's probably what angular should have
done instead is put it in the data
attribute instead of putting in the
class attribute which is primarily used
for you know assigning CSS
classes yeah yeah know for sure that uh
doesn't look like a dangerous attribute
but I guess it is in the angular World
yep exactly pretty crazy Okay cool so
this one this one so you can bypass Dom
purify with this to because Dom purify
automatically at allows anything that
starts with data Dash so data- HX on
error equals alert one or whatever will
will take you all the way there yeah
exactly and this is kind of like a okay
who should fix this should D purify fix
this probably not should hmx fix fix
this maybe they won't but uh they
probably argue something like oh well
you shouldn't do let users uh put HTML
there but yeah I if I I would love love
to see h htx to to drop that support but
I also don't have any background
information on why it's like that from
the start so yeah that is a little bit
odd and I think my take on that is
actually I think Dom purify should add
something for it uh because I think
they're the ones that are more they have
a vested interest in perform in in
performing comprehensive uh HTML
assessment and I think the whole
allowing the data attribute in
particular is a gadget that's been
abused multiple times for D purify so I
I'm wondering why they allow that and
I'm sure they're stuck into it now from
a from a um you know Legacy perspective
but that seems like a little bit of a
questionable decision in the first
place yeah yeah no I agree yeah and I
don't know the reason either or if there
is one yeah so we'll see hopefully D
purify will do something with that or
maybe add a flag like HDMX you know
prevention and just like delete all data
data tags or maybe there is one already
that just removes the whole um data
attribute from uh HD or HTML attributes
I think that would be I think that'd be
good dude this next one kind of looks
crazy though the in the element it's
entitled accessing or accessing
impossible elements and this trigger
looks like you just like essentially
they just concatenate your input with a
bunch of functions what what is this man
yeah so that's how triggers work in the
deep down are you kidding me so no but
they they make them JavaScript functions
basically um
by put putting whatever you have in the
HX trigger with some parsing into an
anonymous function and evalu it so they
get the function back and then assigning
it as that so that's how you can like
break out of it by using like a bunch of
uh and the brackets and stuff oh my gosh
but the reason why this is yeah the
reason why this is interesting though is
that
it's
um so I don't I forget what the proper
name is called I think it's called
something like opaque elements that
aren't supposed to do anything they
shouldn't have like an unload and they
should change the how how the page is
displayed or anything like this but it
has happened multiple times in the past
and I think the most classic one is like
if you have attribute injection inside
of a input that typ
hidden yeah and and if that's the case
in in HDMX
world uh or even meta tags like in my
example uh you can you can access S sp8
wow by just setting a trigger on it but
you don't need to actually make uh the
trigger whatever is supposed to trigger
the trigger
trigger because you can just when it's
trying to build the actual trigger
function in the load of htx you can use
uh okay so let me that's kind of kind of
difficult to explain you're good let me
try to repeat it back to you so I can
make sure that I understand so
essentially what you're doing is you're
adding this HX trigger attribute to the
HTML element and when it processes this
H HX trigger attribute it's
concatenating your input it's doing some
rejects on it or whatever and then
concatenating your input with some other
templatized Anonymous function right and
saying okay you know we'll get this
function eving it taking the function
assigning it to the onload Handler
whatever you're telling it to trigger um
and when it evals it like I'm looking at
the code right here it's like uh it
looks like he's closing off a bunch of
functions um and uh function calls and
that sort of thing and then just adding
alert and then commenting out the rest
of it which is like classic you know uh
context injection here inside of a
JavaScript environment um I just
wouldn't have thought that this is
actually done that way and then
furthermore I wouldn't have thought that
they would would have not considered the
fact that these control characters might
end up in the input like like your curly
bracket and stuff like that to close off
these functions I guess you can't
disallow those because you need to be
able to allow them to do curly brackets
and that sort of thing inside the the
actual function but kind of
odd yeah yeah no I agree and you got
that exactly right and they should have
of course escaped this somehow or like
made sure that okay this is supposed to
be the function body it's not supposed
to break out of our little wrapper here
which is what happened but yeah it was
really fun this one because it reminds
me a lot about the like the good old
days when flash was still a thing and
that would have like a lot of these kind
of problems when it went to like
external interface and it was like
taking something the from the browser or
like sorry from flash world and running
as a JavaScript you can do could do this
stuff like these sort of things wow that
was that was a little before my my time
with this so I didn't actually see much
of that but uh it's cool to see past
lessons uh being reapplied here and and
I will say you know the rest of these
payloads that we're we've talked about
so far in this uh in this episode are
pretty easy to understand you know just
there's the HDMX version of the onload
Handler and you know a simple uh client
side response header that's HX redirect
that allows you to just do window
location.href equals whatever um but
this one is a little bit this one's
pretty fancy so for those of you that
are actually interested in in getting a
good grip on HDMX security and how you
might be able to use this in a bug
Bounty environment definitely check out
the notes where we'll include the actual
payload of how he and it looks like to
me here there's some Rex that's that
you're bypassing because it seems like
it has to be inside of some sort of
array or something like that why is
there the X X and then the square
brackets so if our corre correctly
you're supposed to do like uh it could
be X in said could be like IMG or
something and then it's supposed to be
the the name of the event inside of the
hard brackets ah but the name part can
be used to like escape this templated
function you found this whole little um
yeah okay this little dot do plus rex or
whatever that just allows whatever cool
cool exactly exactly and and the like
the HDMX source code is not that big
either so yeah I encourage people to
jump in and take a look yeah if Yota
we're looking at you man if you're
listening we want to see more more HDMX
stuff I know that OTA in his free time
instead you know when he's not doing his
normal hacking just for fun he just
reviews you know JavaScript source code
Frameworks or JavaScript Frameworks
source code so uh that's one of those
weird
things that makes him what he is um so
when I was looking at this a little bit
so that that sort of sums up the section
there and and I've got a couple comments
as well because I was looking into HTML
or HDMX stuff whenever um you know you
said that we were going to do this
segment um and I I I grabbed a couple
things but I guess I want to ask you
know how did the CTF go and and were
there a lot of solves and any any good
feedback on
this there was like 15 or So Sol for
this this Challenge and yeah like I said
people seem to enjoy it didn't think it
was unfair or or too hard I I guess some
people thought it was too hard until
they solved it and then they thought it
was great yeah as it goes and yeah I had
some good uh how did you discussion with
with some people about their solutions
they had like slightly different
variations how did you how did you
structure the actual challenge you said
it combines some of these
pieces yes so the challenge let me open
the code for the challenge actually so
I'm know what I'm talking about
just a
sec so the what the the application that
I built that they were supposed to accss
was like a random random image viewer so
you press a button and you get you get
to view a random image and there was
like a share share link and that share
link had the
problem U and so the first problem was
that uh this share link took the current
path
uh and uh that's where it made the HX on
request so if you did like present five
C or like present 20 slash it would
become like a protocol relative URI and
then you can make it fetch your own the
main uh and then you would think okay
that means they have xss and they're
done
now but I also of course as we've talked
about had the CSP m
um I still haven't found the code sorry
I'm not very good at multitasking no no
you're good so so you at this point
you've essentially established a way for
them to control a request that's being
made by H HDMX which opens up a whole
new can of worms according to what
you've you've told us uh because a lot
of the functionality is actually um
happening in the responses of these
fetch requests that are being made to
pull HTML down from the server
that's right so it's it's almost like a
client I mean it's a client side path
traversal of sorts but there's not
really a path traversal it just controls
the location of the of the
request yeah yeah
exactly that's right and so then there
was two more things uh the first thing
was the
CSP um which had unsafe but not unsafe
in line oh actually three more things uh
and that you just have to bypass by
instead of doing like on error whatever
you'd have to know that okay I have to
use HX something
here um so that was part two part three
was that the target so when you use HDMX
you X you can specify a Target to say
like okay the HTML that I get back here
should be put in this div or whatever
Target body or you can even do do some
inline uh stuff like Target closest div
and it will like walk up or down cool so
it's pretty pretty nice yeah but my
target was uh something that had HX
disa so if you yeah Tricky Tricky Tricky
so if you only did the U HX on whatever
it wouldn't pop because it would would
be put into a dis disabled
element and so what you had to do was H
you had to either use the HX retarget
request sorry response header or HX
location uh and both of those can be uh
used uh by the server to say like hey
actually this should Target something
else and that that is given
priority yes yes exactly it's telling
hmx like hey ignore the target use this
instead and so that's how they could
avoid the HX disable uh but then there
was one final boss uh so you can make
extensions to to HDMX which is pretty
nice it's like hooks
uh and you can hook a bunch of things
like transform respawns uh and it will
be before it's rendered any HTML it will
be put through your extensions uh it
will be used as a call back and in there
I put the don't
purify any HTML that I fetched yeah dude
this is an dude I can't imagine doing
this CTF and just being like Oh my gosh
why is there like 17
layers yeah but like CTF people are are
good so I have to keep them up by true
somehow um but yeah that was the last
part so I put all all of those together
and you give it to my admin bot that had
like a nice cookie and and you win dude
that sounds like a sick challenge you
know like and maybe we can pivot the
conversation into this a little bit
like I think I missed out a little bit
on the CTF world because I got you know
when I was in college I was just kind of
getting into
hacking again after I sort of stepped
away from it for a little while because
I was I was younger and I was not
hacking responsibly and then I came back
in and my first sort of reintroduction
to it from just outside of my own ideas
in my own you know college was
dogi uh showing me hacker one in bug
Bounty and then I was like this is all I
want to do because I'm also poor and in
college and I need money you know and so
I like never really had that that time
where I was like I'm just like Mega
technically curious and also not
interested in making money particularly
right now um and I think there's a lot
of benefit to doing these ctfs from a um
ability to technically Deep dive
perspective and and just the because
this is the whole thing that you have to
do in bug Bounty as well is like you
have to ingest a new framework a new
product a new API you know all this
stuff so fast
and then find the problems with it and I
think you're forced to do that time and
time again with CF at a very deep
level yeah for sure I agree and uh I
feel like I'm I'm a bit uh lucky to to
have started my journey before there was
back Bounty because otherwise I think I
would have done the same like what
hacking but not for money yeah what do
you mean exactly man it it it it
definitely is tricky though the one
thing that I will say about the CTF like
a little bit like we discussed off air
though is
like the the fact it doesn't help you
with that whole problem of knowing
there's a bug or not knowing there's a
bug like I feel like one of the most
important skills that you have to
develop as a hacker is like your own gut
instinct in your own um understanding
how far you're willing to push to see if
you can make a bug happen um or or
whether there's a bug there or whether
there's a there's not a bug there and
and at the end of the day there's not
always a bug there even if something is
super sketchy um and I think a CTF
there's always a bug there so I think
that I don't know that that one is a
little bit tricky for me is
there's despite the way that it really
equips a lot of hackers ctfs um that one
skill is left undeveloped I
think yeah for sure like there's a lot
of overlap between the skills you can
acquire from Bounty and and CF but they
also have their
own pros and cons right so in CF is
usually very technical and you have to
do a lot of deep dipes uh but you miss
out on like things like Recon and and
also the psychological part that you
were talking about and like there is
100% back here so yeah so yeah that's
for sure and and actually building CF
challenges is it's uh has been for me a
very nice way to learn as well cuz
you're kind of forced
to well use the tools that you're trying
to understand let's say so that's why
I'm that's why I'm switching Frameworks
all the time and also the like languages
I write the backend in yes because like
I I see something somewhere in the
Bounty probably and I'm like okay I
don't understand this my next CTF
challenge I'm going to build in this so
I can understand that's great that's
that's a really good that's a really
good way to balance that out because I
think for me it's just so often times so
push push push with buck Bounty it's
like uh you know I'm not really stepping
aside to do much Dev or you know I guess
my side Venture is a little bit
different right I'm doing a podcast or
running a business or something like
that so um not as much of a another
layer of uh technical side side quest so
to speak um yeah I I think but going
back to that I just want to make this
clear for any listeners that are CTF
players like um the biggest probably
probably the biggest skill that you'll
need to develop as uh going into bug
bounty from the CTF world is that
whether there's a bug here or whether
there's not a bug here intuition and I
think it you will probably almost all
cfers will lean on the side of there
there is a bug here and and keep on
pushing and pushing and pushing and
pushing when at some points you just got
to let it go and uh and move on to
something else because there's always
going to be other sketchy parts of the
application as well and and correct me
if I'm wrong M but I think there are
there are sort of distractions or like
fakes in CTF as well where they're like
send you down One path but it's actually
not the right
path I mean it depends on the stf and
the author I think um there's a lot of
there's a bunch of those but you just
got to learn which cdfs are good I guess
do you do you not like those I I no I
don't like those I try to always have
one path and it's it should be fairly
easy to figure out what you're supposed
to do but it's supposed to be hard to do
it that's how I kind of think and also
it shouldn't involve any guessing
because it's time boxed so that's true
yeah guessing is is definitely not going
to be helping you in a time box
situation there um so yeah but there's
also like one thing that you kind of
lose in in terms of web CF challenges
and also by the way another good thing
about CFS is that if you're in a CF team
you get access to people who know about
other areas of security that isn't used
much in in in bug bount such as reverse
engineering and biner exploitation and
such um which for me has been inval in
invaluable yeah yeah that's it like very
very valuable I don't know in you can't
assign a value to it is is how valuable
it is yes invaluable um yeah no that
that definitely makes sense and the
collaboration piece is huge from the
Bounty perspective as well if you're
fortunate enough to have people to work
with and uh that are really really
talented such as yourself Matias and
actually that that's a perfect a perfect
segue into a little little story from
the latest live hacking event I figured
I'd embarrass Matias on air here
um there was this live hacking event
2018 Vegas where Matias was crushing it
and I was a newbie and uh and I remember
him pulling me aside you know or
actually me pulling him aside and being
like yo was that bug he found and he
shows me this like um this bypass that
he had done to essentially a wa or or a
reverse proxy that was Walling off an
endpoint and uh and he just changed the
case on a character or you know modified
some encoding or something like that and
I was like I hate that this worked I
hate that this I hate this so much you
know like and like how could I have not
have thought to like modify the case or
like change the encoding up and down or
something like that and um you know
recently in a live hacking event I I
found one similar to that and I I in the
show and tell for this uh for this event
for this bug I um I put matias's face on
the last slide and I was like this
little frecker right here and that
stupid smile that he's doing right now
on uh YouTube in my brain just being
like yeah just change the case bro just
change the case from lowercase to Upper
while doing that stupid face is the
reason I never forgot that trick and I'm
always that's funny I need I need a new
trick yeah man it h i just it's just one
of those moments you're like
ah yeah I remember it clearly because I
know I know like nefy I remember he said
the same thing about the same bug so
that was really really fun so
aggravating you know when you were so
close and it's like something as trivial
as like a case Flip or like an encoding
or something like that to get you there
um frustrating um okay before before we
move along because actually you did some
interesting work on um the CDN CGI stuff
that we had been talking about on the
Pod for the past couple weeks in Cloud
flare so um I want to I want to go to
that but did you see so go to the doc
and I actually added this little section
right here where there's like this HX on
depreciated did you so in in the ones
that you have um done in your little
sample section here uh they're all HX
uh-h on colon HTM X colon load or error
whatever and then there's like this
depreciated format which I think might
have been what you were talking about
earlier when when you mentioned the
disable bypass but essentially now the
attribute in this sort of disabled or
just depreciated section um which may
still work or may not work the the
attribute is just HX on and then inside
of that you define some additional stuff
like HTM X onload HTM X whatever and you
can actually Define multiple handlers um
with a new line character which makes
the new line character a uh s character
in these environments right where you
you know if you can use the new line
character it's almost like a double
quote or a single quote in this sort of
context so did you see that at all or do
you does that ring any bells for
you um no but but I'm sure there's more
to find so yeah I didn't even read about
this but yeah I guess that's maybe what
they meant with like the old way to do
it and versus the new with a colum yeah
that that's kind of what I was thinking
cuz it seemed like this might have been
the old way that they did it that you
mentioned in the HX disable um but I was
really surprised to see that you can
actually Define multiple handlers by
putting them on a new line and using sln
in that scenario uh or back slash n
which which will give you you know
another way to define another Handler um
and if you can you know so if you can
finish off the syntax from before add a
sln then you're you're good to continue
um and I wonder how it would handle
errors you know if the first if the
first line had incomplete JavaScript
syntax or whatever and then you jump
down to the second line to find a new
one would that screw the second line or
would it I don't know it's definitely
some area for some cool research here
because there's so many funky things
going
on I'm that
though right that though gets out the
the sniper
rifle locks in ner nerd sniped for sure
um all right man so we'll we'll that's a
good idea that's yeah we'll we'll we'll
go back to that afterwards maybe we'll
do a little research off off um off air
on this let's go ahead and close up this
one with a um with a little chat about
the CDN CGI stuff so I continued some
research on this I mentioned I kind of
gave an update on it on the Pod a while
back um I know that there are some
issues here I just can't seem to find a
bunch of them and um this one seemed
really interesting so you were able to I
know you mentioned at one point a CSP
bypass for Firefox and then this is also
a a subdomain only 307 redirect
yeah yeah so the thing is back in
17 there was some I think you mentioned
it too I think it was like cure 53 or if
it was masato or someone talking about
this and I I looked into it with France
I I I assume let's let's just assume
everything I did was France said he you
guys looked into it so yeah yeah the
sweds looked into it and there was one
uh HTTP only CD and CGI endpoint called
bin W and that work like how trace or
track HTTP methods were supposed to be
implemented so they literally sent back
the exact
request that was coming in interesting
just yeah it just reflected the whole
request and based off of that you could
use it to bypass CSP uh in Firefox you
know by I want to say I saw something
similar to
this oh yeah may maybe like this just
was an idea and I I told masato about
this actually in some other context and
then I forgot about it and then I listed
to the Pod and I was like oh yeah that
thing so I wonder does did you look into
it does this still work
nowadays I don't think so I I couldn't
reproduce it anymore this bin wreck but
I think that was just like some debar
stuff it wasn't officially it I found it
in what I did I think I took all of the
like uh top level not top level domains
but like the Apex uh domains of the
bounty programs that I knew about back
then and then I downloaded like web
archive from those grabed for CDN CGI
and found it on one of them and I was
like oh this is interesting very
interesting yeah I had a similar
approach I just used big query and got
all of it just just in case um but yeah
I want to say I've seen something
similar to bin recently that because I I
see that this bin W doesn't exist
anymore on on uh if you hit a a um Cloud
flare website but I I feel like they
moved it somewhere and I feel like we
might be able to still find it and I
know that there is a trace endpoint um
that will send back some stuff to you
but I think it's not everything and I
know that you mentioned before there was
some like magic you had to do to get the
the data to be valid you had to do like
Dom clobbering or something like that to
do get it to be valid JavaScript that
gets assigned um but there's definitely
some some weird weird stuff to be found
here and then you also mentioned this uh
307 redirect which the fact that you
noted down and put in my freaking
document here Matias a subdomain only
307 open redirect like or like semiopen
redirect right just tells me that have
the right person on the podcast right
now because like of course this is so
interesting having the ability to
specify a 307 you know sort of um
semiopen redirect because um it opens up
so much stuff for redirection of of
things that are are non uh get based um
and so this is a really cool one talk
about how you found
that yeah so I went to the documentation
for cgn CGI stuff I saw that there was
something with like some image uh proxy
stuff and I and then I tested it on my
own page uh that's behind Cloud flare
and it didn't work and I was like H and
then I like Googled that type of URL
like CDN CGI image and I found a bunch
and they worked and then I looked at
their DNS and rightly so they were using
Cloud FL I was like H this must be some
feature that's oped in and turns out it
was called uh Cloud flare images Cloud
flare images yeah Cloud flare image
optimization I think and so you can turn
this on for for your domains and then
you get like a local domain only image
proxy and you can also use uh for
caching and stuff like that right yeah
you can you can cach it on on their
service too so like a CDM yeah maybe
self-explanatory
when we're talking about the CD yeah but
the the interesting part about that is
that you can give it a bunch of uh
um Flags attributes whatever to call
them to tell the the image proxy how to
like scale the image and stuff like this
um but you can also tell it to do some
special stuff like on error
redirect and you can tell it where that
redirect should be um so if you do you
like C then CGI image on error equals
redirect and then a
URL uh it will issue a 307 redirect uh
and that redirect is not bound by like
origin but it is bound by top domain and
I wasn't able to bypass it so you if
you're on like example.com you can make
a 307 to hello. example.com and that
might sound lame but that is very very
useful in use like as like in certain
ssrf scenarios and other bugs too I
guess yeah dude the the first scenario
that comes like HDMX yeah like HDMX you
know client side path traversal um any
sort of scenario where you need an open
redirect but you can't control the query
parameter um you know this is a path
only 307 semiopen redirect right which
will get you to expands your open
redirect chain to any of the
subdomains that's right Frick dude I
love this so much like this is like so
exciting because it's anytime you you're
dealing with a poster and this could
also be used in in a sea surf
environment as well where you're you're
like you're controlling sort of like the
I guess not exactly sees surf
cross it it can allow you to hijack a
post request right via like client side
path Daval and then get that post
request pointed at a different subdomain
at a different path which may trigger a
se- surf on that domain right um yeah
super awesome Gadget here man I'm kind
of pissed that I didn't find this to be
honest um I definitely should be looking
more in the image section I've kind of
so there's image and then there's image
delivery there those are two two of the
interesting sections under um CDN CGI
that I need to look into a little bit
more um but this is a super handy gadget
for anyone uh that's looking to chain
open redirects or something like that um
and so many sites are using Cloud flare
in front of them um so having this in
place is
perfect yeah it's good to have sure good
to have all right man um we are an hour
in uh that is you've dropped enough zero
days for us uh today uh you you have uh
sealed your your spot in uh ctbb history
uh for the most zero days dropped in a
specific episode um HDMX good luck uh
fixing all these this week uh you've got
we're recording this on a Monday we're
dropping it on a Thursday so uh
hopefully they can figure that out in
time um and yeah definitely for for the
listeners keep in mind this um gadget
for the subdomain I'll just say a SE
semiopen redirect 307 request um because
that is a great Gadget in the pocket um
anything you want to close with or shout
out on the way out today
Matias um yeah I want to say I will I
will keep using hmx I really love using
it wow it's just that it's a little bit
disappointing with some insecure
defaults and it's easy to shoot yourself
in the foot but uh other than that the
actual way ways of working and using
HTTP
to as a protocol for transferring
hypertext is nice that's awesome well
way to way to hit him with that uh Mega
geek Zinger there at the end uh on the
way out all right man thanks for coming
on thanks man
peace and and that's a wrap on this
episode of critical thinking thanks so
much for listening and if you want more
critical thinking content head over to
ctbb show/ Discord join the Discord
there's lots of great conversations and
chats going on over there and if you
want to support the show there's the
Discord subscriber tiers which give you
access to master classes amas hack
alongs exclusive scripts and an
exclusive chat Channel with us we'll see
you there